ADENIGBA AHMED ADEFOLARIN

No 4 olarenwaju Oloruntele street, opposite mobil, mile 12, Lagos State +2349011464174

Lameda789@gmail.com

A developer with over a year experience building responsive and interactive web sites, core strength writing HTML5 and CSS3 while been fluent in JavaScript and ReactJS. The aforementioned skills have been put to use while working on both solo as well as collaborative projects some of which are already hosted online.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 12/12/1997 State of Origin: KWARA

L.G.A: IFELODUN Nationality: NIGERIA Marital Status: SINGLE

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Usmanu Danfodiyo University

Sokoto, Sokoto State

Bachelor's Degree (MICROBIOLOGY)

November 2014 – September 2018

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Management System Space

Abuja

Front-end Developer

January 2023 – Presently

working in tandem with the team's lead engineer to ensure the creation of a pixel-perfect user interface with logical responses to give users a seamless experience while upholding excellent coding principles. Additionally, I address technical issues users may encounter while navigating the platform

TIIDELab Abuja

Prefellowship Cohort

March 2022 – April 2022

Using only HTML and CSS, I was able to construct and launch both my personal web portfolio and a contact page for an e-commerce website within the duration of the program. During the program, I was also able to

hone my skills in using Git and GitHub because my team and I were given a group project where the requirement for cooperation necessitated the usage of these tools.

TIIDELab Abuja

Cohort 4 Fellowship

JUNE 2022 - December 2022

I was able to hone my technical skills while I was a fellow by creating a platform for anonymous whistleblowing solutions. My team and I created two different versions of the platform. The version supports JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and ReactJS. During my stay at the fellowship, I got the chance to put my leadership skills to work as head of house because I was responsible for managing the daily activities of other program participants. Furthermore, I worked closely with our program coordinator to make sure that daily operations go off without a hitch.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Familiar with python programming language.
- HTML5 and CSS3
- JavaScript
- Bootstrap
- ReactJS
- Typescript
- · Git and GitHub
- Microsoft Office Packages
- Tailwind
- React Query

SOFT SKILLS

- Critical and Analytical thinking
- · Attention to details
- Leadership skills

•	Digital skills
•	Creative
•	Good communication skills
PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT AND CERTIFICATION	
•	Certificate of completion (TIIDELab Cohort 4 Prefellowship Program (Fundamentals of Software Development))
•	Certificate of proficiency as a Junior Frontend Developer (TIIDELab Cohort 4 Fellowship Program (ITFNEA TSDP, 2022))
•	Outstanding Team Members Honors Award (TIIDELab Cohort 4 Fellowship Program (ITF-NEA TSDP, 2022))
•	Volunteering Service Honors Award (TIIDELab Cohort 4 Fellowship Program (ITF-NEA TSDP, 2022))
REFERENCE	
Available upon request.	

Presentation Skills

Team work